

CONTACT ME AT

Quito, Ecuador

info@francoacg.com

www.francoacg.com

in @francoacg

SKILLS SUMMARY

- PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Highcharts
- React.js, React Native, Vue.js, Redux
- MaterializeCSS, TailwindCSS
- Git Github Gitlab Bitbucket
- Linux commands Docker
- Test Driven Development
- RESTful, Node.js, Express.js, Golang
- Python
- C/C++
- Object Oriented Programming
- Regular Expressions
- MVC
- Native Spanish Speaker and intermediate english speaker

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2016 ACM-ICPC Coding Marathon
- Improved the workflow on the companies I've worked on
- My website where you can find more personal highlights!

HOBBIES

- Develop videogames in my spare times
- Learn new technologies and languages
- Experiment with hardware

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

FRANCO COLMENAREZ

ABOUT ME

I'm a Software Developer with about 3 years of experience working on-site and remotely in Backend and Frontent, developing software solutions for the clients. Learning something new every single day, and helping to other developers to keep growing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Contractor

Amaya Editing (Canada, remotely) | Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

- Backend (PHP, Laravel) and Frontend (Javascript, Vue.js) development
- Unit Testing with Laravel
- Creation of Laravel Artisan commands
- API integrations with Shopify and Astro Loyalty

Software Developer

Aleli Desarrollo (Paraguay, remotely) | Jul 2018 - Sept 2020

- Backend (PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter) and Frontend (Javascript, Vue.js, jQuery) development
- Created a **Docker container** for the project
- Created an Android app for a restaurant in React Native
- Created a project template in Laravel and Vue.js with backend testing
- Deployed systems for multiple clients
- Complex SQL queries and database migrations
- Improved the performance of multiple modules
- Git and Bitbucket with Git-flow

Software Developer

Dago C.A. (Venezuela, on-site) | Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

- Weight control systems
- Backend (PHP and the company's own framework, Node.js, Express.js) and Frontend (HTML/CSS/Javascript, jQuery)
- Team work with Git-flow and Gitlab

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

College IUT-FRP | Venezuela

Software Engineering | 2018

- Programming fundamentals: Pointers, Recursion, Binary trees, Object Oriented Programming
- Web development: HTML/CSS, PHP, Databases

Self-taught education

Programming | 2012 - Infinite

- Online courses and platforms such as Platzi
- Online resources and tutorials
- Personal Projects
- Challenges at Codewars